MORGAN BROOKS

OVERVIEW

Ms. Brooks began tinkering with computers in middle school, and eventually took her first programming class in Python during high school. In college she took a chemical programming class to assist with chemical modeling. After graduating and working in a pharmacy for four years, she realized her passion for the tech field and began taking free online programming classes, as well as an Introduction to Linux class. She has attended RailsBridge and DjangoGirls workshops and is currently teaching herself the skills needed to make her first web application. She contributed to her first open source project on GitHub this October.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2012 - Present Covenant Health

Certified Pharmacy Technician

 Assists pharmacists and surgeons in preparing necessary pharmaceutical needs

2010-2012 University of Tennessee

Student Assistant in the Information Security Office

- Evaluated and redesigned the university's emergency response plan
- Created a method of checking for host redundancies within the university's firewall
- Researched solutions to improve campus IT security

2010 - 2012 Regal Entertainment Group

Floor Staff

2005-2008 EB Games

Third Key Manager

SKILLS

Physical Chemistry

Surface Chemistry

Clean room techniques

Windows

Linux Ubuntu

Git

GitHub

Ruby on Rails

Django Framework

Python

CSS/HTML

Reddit Moderator

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2011

University of TN, Knoxville

Synthesis of Thermally-Exfoliated Graphene Oxide

- Prepared thermally-exfoliated graphene oxide (TEGO) by use of the original Hummer's method
- Lithiated the TEGO for research on its use in nano-scale electronics

2011

University of TN, Knoxville

Cerium Oxide Study

- Cerium oxide was of interest due to its catalytic applications to the water-gas-shift (WGS) reaction in the automobile industry
- Performed temperature programmed oxidation and monitored the increased catalytic activity due to the presence of cerium

EDUCATION

2008-2011

University of TN, Knoxville

- BS in Chemistry
- Minor in Material Science & Engineering

INTERESTS

My hobbies include: running, scuba diving, hiking, working towards a private pilot license, and teaching myself how to program.

CONTACT ME

• Email: mbrooks214@gmail.com

• GitHub: https://github.com/Bravepeanut

Website: http://morganbrooks.net/

Phone: 901.832.7044